edexcelonline.com 2017-11-20

# Privacy policy | Pearson UK

**Here, you can find out how we safeguard your information and how we use it to improve our products and services for the benefit of all our customers and website users.  **

(Updated 29 August 2017)

The nature of our business means that, from time to time, we’ll require some personal details from our customers and website users.

The data we collect could just be a name and an email address, but depending on your level of engagement with Pearson, it could be much more than that.

The personal information you’ve shared with us, along with data on how you use our websites - what you search for and what preferences you select, for example - help us to better understand our customers as a group and as individuals. This in turn helps us to provide a range of products and services that meet your needs.

### How we protect your data

When you share your personal information with any company, you have a right to expect that information to be treated with total confidentiality. 

Your privacy is extremely important to us. We’re committed to protecting any personal information you’ve given us, and we comply with all relevant data protection laws.

This means that:

  * We take full responsibility for the information we hold about you  

  * We will protect your privacy at all times  

  * We will never sell your personal information  

Whether you’ve supplied your personal details online, by phone or text, by email or in a letter, we will never use them without a lawful reason to do so. We’ll use them for the purposes for which they were initially requested and as fully explained in this Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy.

These policies explain how your personal data is being managed and safeguarded by us, including:

  * what information we collect about you  

  * how we collect and use this information  

  * how we safeguard the information you’ve provided  

  * how to report abuse

At Pearson, we know that you care how your personal information is used and we appreciate that you trust us to do that carefully and sensibly.

This Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we and other companies in our group collect and use your personal information. We want you to make informed decisions when using our websites and any features on them, including any registration and e-commerce services.

This Privacy Policy applies to all the pages on our sites linking to this Privacy Policy and any features of them and any e-commerce, purchasing or other areas which require registration on our sites. However, it won’t apply to any third-party sites which are linked to our sites. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any such sites that you visit as we are not responsible for them.

When we refer to our website or sites, we mean any of our websites or applications from which you have accessed this Privacy Policy.

We have included full details of who we and our group companies are at the end of this Privacy Policy.

Personal information that we collect may include your name, contact details (phone numbers, email address and addresses), your date of birth, job, course information, your personal interests, credit card or billing information, shopping selections and data about the pages you visit and your other activity on our site, as well as any other personal information relating to you that you supply to us. 

Some of our sites may also collect other information that you supply to us, such as information relating to your education, skills or job experience, where relevant in the context of the site or the services provided through the site. Except where stated otherwise on the site at the time such personal information is submitted, it is only processed for the purposes for which you have submitted it to us.   

We collect your information in two ways:

1\. Personal information you choose to disclose. You may, for example, provide us with your information when you post something on our site, when you register for any features on our site that require registration, when you contact us (online or offline) or when you order goods or services from us.

2\. Information collected by us when you interact with our site, or when you open our email communications. We use cookies (a small piece of computer code that we store for a period of time on your computer or mobile device) and other similar technologies to collect this information. To find out more, please visit our Cookie Policy page.

In a separate automatic operation the web server will collect your IP address and browser type and details of the website, application or email communication you came from before entering our site. This information is used to:

  * work out how many times our site has been visited
  * record which parts of our site have been visited so we can improve the content and layout of the site
  * understand the effectiveness of our email communications.

We may from time to time supply this data to third parties in an anonymised form for uses in connection with our site.

We and our group companies may use your personal information, for example, to provide you with the relevant, to process your online purchases, to inform you about products and services offered by us and our group companies, to improve the products and services offered to you, for market research purposes, for marketing, statistical or analytical purposes to invite you to participate in surveys, discussions and prize draws and ask for your views on our services via online surveys and discussion forums, to detect, prevent or investigate security breaches or fraud and otherwise to better meet the needs and preferences of our customers. 

We will not allow unrelated third parties to use your personal information for marketing without your consent. Where we rely on your consent, you have the right to withdraw it at any time. 

We also use personal information to build marketing profiles, audit how our sites are used, and to help with the strategic development of our sites. When doing so, we remove any direct identifiers. 

Participation in surveys and discussion forums is entirely voluntary. You may unsubscribe from being contacted for these purposes at any time. Survey information will be used for market research with the aim of improving our services.

We will show your username on any content you submit or post on our sites (including discussions, bulletin boards and forums).  

We will not send you marketing emails if you have opted out of receiving them. Any marketing emails we send you will include an unsubscribe link at the end of the email. 

Some Pearson sites also provide contact details you may use if you want to contact us by email, post or telephone in order to unsubscribe. In addition, some Pearson sites have a "My Account" page where you can choose whether or not to receive marketing communications from us.

We seek to protect the safety of all your personal information by implementing appropriate technical and organisational measures. For example, provided your browser accepts Secure Sockets Layer encryption, we seek to protect your payment information against unauthorised access through a secure server. Where we use third parties to process personal information, we require them to ensure the safety of your information. We use appropriate security measures on our own systems, but the internet is not a secure medium and we cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted via the internet.

Any personal information that you voluntarily post on a public area of our site, such as a bulletin board or discussion forum, or an interactive area requiring registration and/or subscription, may be collected and used by others. Please be careful what personal information you disclose in this way. You understand that we cannot control the actions of other users.

We will never sell your personal information. We may disclose and share your personal information:

  * with our group companies
  * any entity which acquires any part of our business  

  * our service providers (including, for example, credit reference agencies and payment processors, distributors/agents of our products, suppliers who develop or host our sites)
  * third-party search engines that may index user profile pages and usernames as part of the URL of the user profile page by default if required or permitted by law
  * relevant third parties (such as your employer, your school, your internet service provider, law enforcement agencies) if we reasonably believe you may be in breach of the law (e.g. if you have posted defamatory content on our sites) or if required to do so in accordance with applicable law
  * other third parties with your consent

We may transfer your personal information to other countries around the world, including countries outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA"), which may not have the same data protection laws as those of the country where you access our sites. Where we transfer your personal information to countries outside of the EEA we will take appropriate steps to ensure your personal information is afforded the same level of protection as described in this Privacy Policy.   

If you are under 18, please be sure to read this Privacy Policy with your parent or guardian and ask them questions about anything you don’t understand. Please get their permission before you provide Pearson with any personal information.

Any improper collection or misuse of personal information is in violation of this Privacy Policy and of our Legal Notice. Please report it by emailing [UKDataProtection@pearson.com](mailto:UKDataProtection@pearson.com).

You agree not to misuse any personal information available on our Site or to gather it or use robots or other automated scripts, codes or functionalities to do so.

We may immediately suspend or terminate your access to our site without notice if we become aware that you are in breach of applicable terms and conditions of use or of this Privacy Policy.  

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will always include the date of a new version so that you know when there has been a change. If you don’t agree to the changes, please don’t continue to use our site or provide us with your personal information.

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or the data we hold about you, or you wish to ensure that the data we hold about you is accurate and kept up to date, please do not hesitate to contact us at:

Data Protection Manager  
Pearson  
80 Strand  
London  
WC2R 0RL  
United Kingdom

\- or email us at [UKDataProtection@pearson.com](mailto:UKDataProtection@pearson.com).

This Privacy Policy is provided by Pearson Education Limited (registered number 872828, registered office 80 Strand, London, WC2R 0RL, United Kingdom) on its own behalf, and on behalf of its group companies.

References in this Privacy Policy to “Pearson”, “we”, “us”, “our” or similar refer to Pearson Education Limited or whichever Pearson group company is operating the relevant website.

Our “group companies” mean companies which are under common control with Pearson Education Limited by Pearson Plc, including without limitation, Pearson Assessment & Information GmbH, Pearson Education Inc, Pearson College Limited, Pearson Education Deutschland GmbH, Pearson Education Schweiz AG, Pearson Educación S.A, Pearson Education France SAS, Pearson Education Benelux BV, Pearson Education Hellas SA, Pearson Italia SpA, Pearson Central Europe Sp Zoo, Pearson Education South Asia Ltd, Pearson Education Asia Ltd, Pearson Education Japan KK, Pearson Education Korea Ltd, Pearson Australia Group Pty Ltd, Pearson New Zealand Ltd, Pearson South Africa Pty Ltd, Pearson Education de Mexico SA de CV, Pearson Education de Colombia Ltda, Pearson Education do Brazil Ltda.
